MAKSYM TSYBULSKYI DEVOPS/SRE

Sacramento, CA 95842 · 916-578-86-78 tomahawksmail@gmail · LinkedIn Profile · GitHub · WebSite

SUMMARY

I am an engineer with over 15 years of experience in IT. In total more than 12 years held the position of head of the IT department. My main qualities are self-management, responsibility and time-management. I always try to work for the result. I have completed a DevOps engineering course and I want to find a new job. I am always happy to learn something new and share my knowledge among my colleagues.

EXPERIENCE

12/2012 - 03/2022 HEAD OF IT DEPARTMENT/ ARCHITECT

CLINIC OF SAINT CATHERINE UKRAINE, ODESA

- Creation of the entire infrastructure of the enterprise (purchase and configuration of equipment)
- Preparation and partial transfer of services to the cloud (AWS and Vodafone)
- Maintenance and backup of multiple databases (MySQL and MS SQL)
- Installation and maintenance of 2 high-load RDP servers
- Maintenance of the enterprise Active Directory, setting policies for user groups (about 600 users)
- Setting up Debian, CentOS and Ubuntu with Ansible
- Build services through a combination of Terraform to provision infrastructure and Ansible. All sources are stored in GitHub.
- Reduced the monthly costs by removing unnecessary servers and databases
- Set up and maintained a 98% uptime of a network of 30 Linux servers, 6 NGINX servers, Cron Jobs
- Install and maintain multiple virtualized services in the cloud and on your own server fleet
- Automation and optimization of processes using Python
- Development of a system (Python3+Flask) for call statistics in a call center
- Hosting and domain management, zone setup, mail server administration (8 domains)
- Construction and maintenance of IT infrastructure of the enterprise

05/2010 – 10/2012 HEAD OF IT DEPARTMENT CHAIN OF RETAIL STORES "VIRTUS" UKRAINE, ODESA

01/2006 - 06/2010

CHIEF ENGINEER

SECURITY SYSTEMS INTEGRATOR

"AGENT-SB"

UKRAINE, ODESA

-Design and installation of security systems

EDUCATION

2000 - 2006

ODESSA NATIONAL
TELECOMMUNICATIONS ACADEMY

BY O.S.POPOV UKRAINE, ODESA

COURSES & CERTIFICATES

02/2022 HILLEL IT school <u>DevOps</u>

01/2023 AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials

01/2022 TP-LINK CERTIFIED PARTNER

SKILLS

- Linux: Ubuntu, Debian
- MS Windows Server: AD, DNS, GPO, SMB
- Networking: Subnetting, TCP, UDP, HTTP(S), IPSec
- IaC: Terraform
- SQL: MySQL (MariaDB), MS SQL Server
- Scripts: Python3
- Version Control System: Git, GitHub
- Containers: Docker, Docker Compose
- Clouds: AWS VPC, AWS CLI
- Configuration Management: Ansible
- Virtualization: VMware, Oracle VM Virtual Box, Vagrant

BACHELOR, Information Communication Networks

01/2023 AWS Networking Basics

12/2021 AWS TECHNICAL ESSENTIALS

01/2023 AWS Networking Basics

Basic skills

- CI/CD: Jenkins, Git Lab, GitHub
- Scripts: Bash
- Web server: NGINX
- Orchestration: Kubernetes, Docker Swarm
- Observability: Logging with ELK Stack
- WSGI: Gunicorn+Flask
- Synchronization: Rsync